Violeta Sol Arias Hours

Salta - Salta, Argentina

(+54) 9 3875377584

Full Stack Developer

violehours@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/violetasolariashours

GitHub: https://github.com/VioleHours

Porfolio: https://violetahours.vercel.app/

TECH SKILLS: Javascript, Typescript, Python

FRONT-END: HTML5, Css3, ReactJs, ReduxJs, NextJs, TailwindCss, Angular, Bootstrap, Sass, Zustand

BACK-END: NodeJs, Express, Sequelize

DATABASES: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase

TOOLS: Git/GitHub, VSCode, VisualStudio, Slack, Trello, Jira, Figma AGILE: Scrum

WHOIAM

I am a Full Stack web developer and UX/UI Designer with a background in Audiovisual Production. I have experience in both Frontend and Backend development, with skills in agile methodologies, GIT, and data structures. In addition to technical skills such as JavaScript, React, NodeJs, and Angular, I have worked on individual and group projects, which has helped me develop soft skills such as good communication, teamwork, adaptability, and problem-solving.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer - Countries PI

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Individual Project

In this project, I developed a SPA (Single Page Application) about countries and activities which can be created, assigned, and deleted. It also includes combined filters, pagination, and controlled forms, among other features.

Front: React, Redux, Css Back: NodeJs, Express

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize

Full Stack Web Developer - PF e-latam

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Our project is an innovative e-commerce platform designed specifically for the dynamic and vibrant Latin American market. This platform serves as a virtual marketplace where administrators oversee business operations, while users interact with a wide range of products, reviews, and ratings. Users are free to explore an extensive catalog of products and make informed purchasing decisions.

Front: React, ReduxToolkit, Css, Vite

Back: NodeJs, Express.

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE.

Frontend Developer DASCalendar · Part-time

Oct 2023 - Mar 2024

• Frontend development of a website using React and TypeScript as main technologies.

Odoo Developer InkuA · Internship

May 2023 - Oct 2023

Development of websites for NGOs using Odoo and Python primarily.

Full Stack Teaching Assistant

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

- Coordinating a group of students to achieve integration into the study team.
- Assisting in exercise resolution and promoting group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Proposing ideas for improving Bootcamp processes.

Camera Assistant

Nov 2018 - Mar 2020

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

Catholic University of Salta

- Responsible for the proper maintenance of the camera during filming.
- Operation of television studio cameras for the courses of Broadcasting and Production and Direction for Radio and Television.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- UX/UI Design. Codo a Codo. 198 hours of theoretical-practical training. Aug 2023 Dec 2023.
- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 800 hours of theoretical-practical training. Oct 2022- Jul. 2023.
- Bachelor's Degree in Image and Sound. Catholic University of Salta. 19/50 approved subjects. 2018-2020

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

- Fashion Design/Personal Image Consulting. Roberto Piazza Salta High Fashion and Comprehensive Beauty Institute. 2021-2022
- Production and Direction for Radio and Television. Catholic University of Salta. 2019-2020

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native.
- English B2 Intermediate.